Prachi Sharma (1) Featured

Software Developer seeking opportunity in Software Dev, Software Design, Data Structures, SDLC, Java, J2EE, SQL, HTML, Spring, Hibernate, Jenkins, Apache Tomcat, springboot, spring, microservices, Telecom, Billing, oss, bss, crm, REST, RESTful. web services



Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Software Developer

Current Company: Amdocs Development Centre India LLP Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: Integrated PG [CSE]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Pune, Gurgaon Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Key Skills: Software Development, Software Design, Data

Structures, SDLC, J2EE, SQL, HTML, Eclipse, Remedy, Spring, SpringBoot, Hibernate, Jenkins, Java, JSP

Servlets, C, DBMS, J2Ee, Core Java, Advanced Java, Beans, Microservices, Spring Boot, Rest, RESTful web service, Web

Services

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Persistent professional equipped with 2 years of comprehensive experience in Telecom industry. Provide strong technical direction across multiple projects. Responsible and articulate individual with strengths in solutions optimization, mobile and cloud solutions and global project management

Work Experience

Amdocs Development Centre India LLP as Software Developer

Feb 2019 to Till Date

2 years of experience in the Telecom domain of designing, developing, and enhancing Billing product.

Involved in all phases of SDLC, from analysis, design, development, testing, implementation and maintenance.

Technical as well as functional knowledge of Billing product

Client: Elisa, Finland

Technologies: Core Java, Unix, SQL Duration: Feb 2019 - Dec 2019

Client: Three, Ireland

Technologies: Core Java, SpringBoot, Hibernate, Unix, SQL, Python

Duration: Dec 2019- till date

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from LAKSHMI NARAIN COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY - BHOPAL in 2018

PG: Integrated PG (CSE) from Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya (RGPV), Bhopal in 2018

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
CORE JAVA	7	2020	2 Year(s)
MySQL		2020	2 Year(s)
HP UNIX		2020	2 Year(s)
Spring		2020	2 Year(s)
spring boot		2020	2 Year(s)
Hibernate		2020	2 Year(s)
Rest Services		2020	2 Year(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
english				
hindi				

Projects

Project Title: Telecom billing Three

Client: Three Ireland

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2019 - Till Date Project Location: Pune Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Role: Programmer Team Size: 17

Skill Used: Core Java, Hibernate, Spring, Spring Boot, Unix Shell Scripting, SQL,

Role Description: * Involved in all phases of SDLC, from analysis, design, development, testing,

implementation and maintenance.

* Technical as well as functional knowledge of Billing product

Project Details: Billing product of Three.

Working on the self-service tool, wherein people can pay bills, order service relevant to their mobile service.

Project Title: Telecom billing Elisa

Client: Elisa

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Feb 2019 - Dec 2019 Project Location: Pune Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 15

Skill Used: Core Java, Unix, SQL, C

Role Description: Involved in all phases of SDLC, from analysis, design, development, testing,

implementation and maintenance.

Technical as well as functional knowledge of Billing product

Project Details: Client: Elisa, Finland Technologies: C, Core Java, Unix, SQL

Duration: Feb 2019 - Dec 2019

2 years of experience in the Telecom domain of designing, developing, and enhancing Billing product.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time